# Shanmukh Aditya Yenikapati

(551)6896998 | shanmukh.yenikapati@rutqers.edu | linkedin.com/in/shanmukh-y/ | github.com/shanmukhaditya/

#### **SUMMARY**

Accomplished and multi-skilled Computer Science graduate student with more than 2 years of proven professional experience as a Database Developer. Excellent problem-solving skills and demonstrated ability to perform well in a team. Seeking an internship as a Software Engineer.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **Rutgers University-New Brunswick**

09/2021-Present

Master of Science in Computer Science, Machine Learning, CGPA- 3.83

## VNR Vignana Jyothi Institute of Engineering and Technology

08/2015-05/2019

Bachelor of Technology, CGPA- 8.32

Served as student coordinator for Americans Society of Mechanical Engineers(ASME)

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Programming Languages: Python, C, C++, C#, Java, Javascript, T-SQL, PL/SQL, HTML5
- Tools and Frameworks: Azure, GIT, Tensorflow, Pandas, NodeJS, ASP.NET

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Faculty Survey Assistant**

10/2021-Present

Office of Institutional Research, Rutgers University-New Brunswick

- Developed a tool using python that extracts data from PDF to Microsoft excel
- This tool is to be hosted on our University website

#### **Database Developer**

Tata Consultancy Services

- Worked in Agile environment to develop stored procedures which are used to retrieve/ modify/ insert appropriate data for business processes
- Migrated database code from on-premise (PL/SQL) to Azure cloud(T-SQL)
- Used SQL window functions to mimic production data

#### **RELATED PROJECTS**

#### Image Generation using GAN

12/2020-12/2020

Created an image generation model that generates human images using Kaggle's celebrity image dataset

#### Intelligent Chatbot 12/2020-12/2020

- Created a deep learning model based on NMT that is trained using Reddit chat data
- A scoring system has been integrated so that inappropriate responses, racial discrimination, abuse are eliminated
- Integrated the model into discord server to have an interactive interface

CartPole

Coursera

01/2021-01/2021

A reinforced learning model which learns to balance the pole on its own

### PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

6.S191 Intro to Deep Learning  MIT-OCW	02/2020-03/2020
6.006 Introduction to Algorithms  MIT-OCW	05/2020-06/2020
Neural Networks and Deep Learning	01/2020-02/2020
Coursera  Machine Learning	10/2019-11/2019
Coursera	
Artificial Intelligence: Search Methods for Problem Solving NPTEL	07/2018-10/2018
Programming, Data Structures and Algorithms using Python	08/2018-09/2018